ソーシャルネットワークで
何ができますか？
What can you do on a social network?
You can connect with people;
みんなとつながることができます
しかも大勢の人とです
(a lot{
share your photos;
写真をシェアしたり—
冗談を言ったり—
tell jokes;
post your thoughts on,
いろんなことについて
自分の意見を言ったり—
well, just about anything;
みんなが今何しているかが分かります
And see what all your friends are up to.
It’s pretty easy
すっごく簡単—
でも そこが問題です
—and that’s th{
Sometimes it’s a little too {
簡単過ぎることがあるんです
You see, a social network may look harmless,
害がないように思えるかもしれません
but once you log in,
でも 一度ログインしたら気を付けて！
watch out!
It could be a dangerous place.
危険がいっぱいです
So if your parents
allow you to have an account,
ですから 親にアカウントの取得を
許可してもらえたら—
you have to be smart,
十分注意して利用してください
social-network smart.
Follow the front-page rule.
基本的なルールを守りましょう
Don’t post anything
テレビや新聞のニュースに載せられたら
困るようなものを投稿してはなりません
that you wouldn’t want to see on the TV news
or the front page of the newspaper.
And that includes
personal information like
個人情報も載せてはなりません
your phone number,
電話番号とか 住所とか 学校名などです
where you live,
and where you go to school.
Never tell people when you’re not home
いつ家にいないとか
いつ旅行に出かけるとかも—
or when you’re going on vacation.
書き込んではいけません
It may seem harmless,
問題がないように思える
かもしれませんが—
but that’s exactly the kind of information
犯罪者にとっては—
thieves can use to break into your house
泥棒に入ったり
あなたになりすましたりするのに—
or even steal your identity!
おいしい情報なのです！
Now let’s look at your reputation.
あなたの評判についてはどうですか？
Your photos and comments say a lot about you.
写真やコメントは
あなたについて多くを語ります
So, if you’ve made a fool of yourself, ask,
恥ずかしいものを載せたら—
それを見た人はあなたについて
どんな印象を持つでしょうか？
‘Is this how I really want people to view me
—not just now but in the future,
将来 仕事の面接の結果にも
影響するかもしれません
like at a job interview?’
At Proverbs 22:1,
聖書の箴言 22章1節によると—
the Bible says a good reputation
良い評判には
銀や“金”よりも価値があります
is ‘worth more than silver and gold.’
Don’t let that Delete key fool you.
いつでも消せると思ってはなりません
Posting something on any social network
一度投稿したものは
いつまでも残るからです
is kind of like writing in permanent ink.
OK, so you’re careful
about what {
何をシェアするかだけでなく—
だれとシェアするかにも注意が必要です
Now think
about who {
Who are your friends?
どんな友達がいますか？
Some people have hundreds of online friends.
SNSの友達が
数百人 数千人という人もいます
Some have thousands.
多ければ多いほど良い
ということでしょうか？
So you may think,
‘The more friends, the better, right?’
Actually, no!
そうではありません
思い違いをしていると
大変なことになります
That kind of thinking
can blow up in your face.
You see,
when you connect with online friends,
オンラインで友達とつながっている時には—
you are also indirectly connecting
with their{
その人の友達とも
間接的につながっています
そして その友達の友達にもです
And their friends’ {
That means
you may find yourself seeing posts
つまり 全く知らない人—
from people you don’t even know
あなたとはモラルや信条が違う人たちの
投稿も見えてしまうのです
—people whose morals and beliefs
may be different from yours.
They may use bad language
汚い言葉を使う人や—
or post about things you know are wrong.
良くないものを投稿する人もいます
Those just aren’t the kind of friends
you want to hang around with
そんな人たちと一緒にいたいとは
思わないはずです
—not even online.
ネット上でも同じです
And there’s another danger.
別の危険もあります
At Psalm 26:4,
聖書の詩編 26編4節によると—
the Bible warns about people
“who hide what they are.”
“自分がどんな者かを隠す”人がいます
They pretend to be someone they are not
別人になりすまして すごく親切な
ふりをするのです
and may seem super friendly,
but they can be dangerous.
そこに落とし穴があります
So when it comes to friends,
you need to be picky.
ですから 友達はよく選びましょう
The safest friends online
安全なのは—
オフラインですでに知っている人を
友達にすることです
are ones you already know offline.
There’s one more thing to think about:
もうひとつ大切なのは 時間です
It has to do with your time.
Checking out the latest posts
can be addictive.
最新の投稿をチェックしていると
きりがありません
So let’s set some limits,
ですから 制限を設けましょう
and don’t let your online l{
実生活に影響が及ばないように
するのです
get in the way of your real{
You know,
connecting with others online
SNSで楽しく安全に
みんなとつながっているには—
can be fun and safe
潜んでいる危険に
よく注意していなければなりません
as long as you look out for all the dangers.
So the next time you log in, be smart,
次回 ログインする時は—
賢く スマートに利用してくださいね
social-network smart.